[{
        "question": "According to hindu mythology, who is the father of Shani",
        "option1": "Shiva",
        "option2": "Pavan",
        "option3": "Chandra",
        "option4": "Surya",
        "answer": "Surya"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who swallowed the poison known as 'Halahala', produce during Samudra Manthan",
        "option1": "Vishnu",
        "option2": "Indra",
        "option3": "Shiva",
        "option4": "Parvati",
        "answer": "Shiva"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Mahabharat, Ganga was the wife of",
        "option1": "Vichitravirya",
        "option2": "Shantanu",
        "option3": "Chitrangada",
        "option4": "Vishvamitra",
        "answer": "Shantanu"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Ramayan, Meghanath is the other name of",
        "option1": "Ravan",
        "option2": "Indrajit",
        "option3": "Vibhishana",
        "option4": "Hanuman",
        "answer": "Indrajit"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who assuming the form of a golden deer to help Ravana to kidnapped Sita",
        "option1": "Subahu",
        "option2": "Meghanath",
        "option3": "Maricha",
        "option4": "Dushana",
        "answer": "Maricha"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who build the palace for Pandavas at khandavprastha",
        "option1": "Krishna",
        "option2": "Balaram",
        "option3": "Vishwakarma",
        "option4": "Maya",
        "answer": "Maya"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who broke the teeth of Lord Ganesha",
        "option1": "Kubera",
        "option2": "Parshuram",
        "option3": "Indra",
        "option4": "Shiva",
        "answer": "Parshuram"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Lord of the Dance 'Nataraj', is a depiction of the God",
        "option1": "Shiva",
        "option2": "Vishnu",
        "option3": "Brahma",
        "option4": "Krishna",
        "answer": "Shiva"
    },
    {
        "question": "'Vrishakethu' is the son of",
        "option1": "Bhima",
        "option2": "Arjun",
        "option3": "Karna",
        "option4": "Kripacharya",
        "answer": "Karna"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which day of Kurukshetra War, Bhishma was put on deathbed of arrows by Arjun",
        "option1": "5th Day",
        "option2": "8th Day",
        "option3": "10th Day",
        "option4": "16th Day",
        "answer": "10th Day"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who gifted the Shiv Dhanush to King Janak, broken by Lord Rama at Sita swayamvar",
        "option1": "Shiv",
        "option2": "Nandi",
        "option3": "Vishnu",
        "option4": "Parashuram",
        "answer": "Parashuram"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who narrates the action of Kurukshetra to Dhritarashtra live during the battle",
        "option1": "Vidur",
        "option2": "Sanjay",
        "option3": "Ganesh",
        "option4": "Gandhari",
        "answer": "Sanjay"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many children was born to Devaki and Vasudev before Krishna birth",
        "option1": "3",
        "option2": "5",
        "option3": "7",
        "option4": "8",
        "answer": "7"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the only sister of 100 Kaurav brothers ",
        "option1": "Ulupi",
        "option2": "Uttara",
        "option3": "Hidimba",
        "option4": "Dussala",
        "answer": "Dussala"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one is the feminine form of Lord Vishnu helping devas to retain their immortality",
        "option1": "Aditi",
        "option2": "Mohini",
        "option3": "Padma",
        "option4": "Lakshmi",
        "answer": "Mohini"
    },
    {
        "question": "From which forest Sita was abducted by the Ravana",
        "option1": "Ashok Vatika",
        "option2": "Kamyaka Forest",
        "option3": "Dandaka forest",
        "option4": "None of the above",
        "answer": "Dandaka forest"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the real name of Valmiki, the writer of Ramayana",
        "option1": "Basuki",
        "option2": "Devabrata",
        "option3": "Ratnakar",
        "option4": "Partha",
        "answer": "Ratnakar"
    },
    {
        "question": "For how many days was the battle of kurukshetra was fought",
        "option1": "12",
        "option2": "18",
        "option3": "15",
        "option4": "10",
        "answer": "18"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the final incarnation of Lord Vishnu in his Dashavatara",
        "option1": " Kalki",
        "option2": "Parashuram",
        "option3": "Krishna",
        "option4": "Kurma",
        "answer": " Kalki"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which Yuga, Krishna was born",
        "option1": "Satya Yuga",
        "option2": "Treta Yuga",
        "option3": "Dwapara Yuga",
        "option4": "Kali Yuga",
        "answer": "Dwapara Yuga"
    }
]